Biswanath Nanda

Senior Solution Consultant

Seeking position as Sales Consultant in which I can be a major contributor, enhance my skills, and broaden my areas of expertise. I am enthusiastic about continuing my experience and/or advancing to new areas. I have proven my ability to meet challenges with 6.11 years of diverse experience, and I am now ready for a new challenge where we can help enterprise in making best decisions for better business.



biswanath.nanda.ds@gmail.com

+31651126735

297 Mr G Groen van Prinstererlaan Oranjebaan, Amstelveen 1181 TV, Amsterdam, Nerherlands

biswanat.blogspot.in/

linkedin.com/in/biswanath-nanda in

biswanath.nanda.ds@gmail.com 🔕

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant in Advanced Analytics ,EPM and BI

ING Bank (as a direct employee of HCL Technologies Netherlands)

06/2018 – Present

Amsterdam

Achievements/Tasks

- Working as Solution Consultant in EPM,BI and Analytics for managing on-boarding and Platform services at ING.
- Developing Hyperion Planning and HPCM modules.
- Working with FP & A team in gathering functional requirements for Banking Risk Applications and developing Hyperion Planning Applications.
- Worked on automating process using DevOps tools.
- Worked on designing reports and visualizations using R scripting.
- Installation and Configuration on Python 3.7.0
- Preparing Anaplan Models as an enhancement to inhouse budgeting capabilities.
- Designing Analytics dashboard on the top of Finance Data and helping customers in their forecast process.

SKILLS

Oracle EPM Oracle Cloud Oracle Sales

Data Science DevOps Anaplan Google Cloud

Linux Scripting Oracle Analytics Cloud

Oracle BI and Data Visualisation

IOT

HONOUR AWARDS

Platform Specialist of the Quarter by Oracle Senior Vice President Sales and CSM Hamidou Dia 🗗

Oracle India PVT LTD

Customer Delight award in Oracle Cloud Solutions Hub
Oracle India PVT LTD

Going Extra Mile Award in Oracle Cloud Solution Hub
Oracle India PVT LTD

Manger's Choice Award
IBM India Pvt LTD

LANGUAGES

English • • • •

INTERESTS

IOT Active participant in RLE data science academy

Beginner data-science enthusiast in Kaggle.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solution Engineer in Sales in EPM, BI and Analytics at Oracle North America Sales Cloud Solutions Hub ORACLE INDIA PVT. LTD.

08/2017 - 06/2018

Bangalore,India

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked as Solution Engineer in Sales and Solution Development in EPM,BI and Analytics division for ORACLE North America Cloud Solution Engineering Hub.
- Performed end-to-end configuration and integration of IOT services, Big data cloud services and OAC Data visualization to display predictive analytics and machine learning.
- Worked as key member in preparing proposals to sell Oracle PaaS and Oracle SaaS products.
- Worked as a Key member in finalising Sales Deals for Oracle PBCS and Oracle Analytics cloud.
- Worked in developing Regression and binary classification models using Python.
- In-depth knowledge in configuring Oracle cloud (PAAS and SAAS) instance.
- Implemented What if forecast models and integrated the Essbase data with Data visualization to build predictive modelling with Essbase data, which helped customer to analyse the Sales trend.
- Implemented Quality control charts using R and Oracle Data Visualization desktop.

Package Solution Consultant IBM India PVT LTD

03/2015 - 07/2017

Kolkata.India

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked as SME and performed Hyperion Planning application development and administrative activates.
- Worked as a module lead and was responsible for analyzing and troubleshooting HFM production support issues.
- Developed Unix shell scripting automation.
- Developed ETL integrations using Oracle Data Integrator.
- Preparing development estimates and write ups.

Systems Engineer TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

09/2011 – 03/2015

Kolkata,India

Achievements/Tasks

- worked as a team member and work a single point of contact for supporting Planning applications, DRM Applications, HFM application and ODI.
- Responsible for requirement gathering technical and functional issue debugging for forecasting planning applications.
- Designing forecast models in Hyperion Planning.

CERTIFICATES

Oracle Certified Hyperion Planning Certified Implementation Specialist.

CERTIFICATES

Oracle Certified Hyperion Financial Management Implementation specialist.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Telecommunication Engineering
Orissa Engineering
College,Bhubaneswar,India

05/2007 – 06/2011